Guide to the James Boyer Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
James Boyer collection
1773-1841
MS 672
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
3
A collection of photostatic copies of letters (1779-1784) written to James Boyer, artilleryman and commissary officer, during the Revolutionary War. Correspondents include his brother, Peter Boyer, Samuel Hodgdon (1745-1824), Richard Frothingham (1748-1819), Ebenezer Stevens (1713-1798) and Henry Knox (1750-1806). Also included are photostatic copies of miscellaneous documents and papers "found in the Boston Post Office" relating to the Revolution.
Boyer, James
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from Beinecke Rare Book Library, 1973.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The James Boyer collection consists of photostatic copies of letters (1779-1784) written to James Boyer during the Revolutionary War. James Boyer served in an artillery component under Ebenezer Stevens; he also served in a commissary office until the end of the war. Correspondents include Peter Boyer, his brother, a member of the Committee of Correspondence, Safety, and Inspection in Boston, Samuel Hodgdon (1745-1824), Richard Frothingham (1748-1819), and Ebenezer Stevens (1713-1798). Also included in this collection are photostatic copies of miscellaneous documents and papers relating to the Revolution which, in 1929, were described by the donor, Maj. Preston Brown, as being "found in the Boston Post Office."
Massachusetts -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783; Boyer, James
- Inventory
  - [Papers found in the Boston Post Office]
    - Passport issued by Col. Suttelough, Q. M. Gen. To Luke Johnson, 1778 February 15 (Box 1)
    - Isaac Barron's statement of service in the American Revolution and plea for a pension, witnessed by John Davis, 1818 April 14 (Box 1)
    - Certificate of Service in the Revolutionary War for Isaac Barron, signed by John Davis; Boston, 1818 September (Box 1)
    - Notification of appointment of Issaac Barne to the Wheel Wright company, signed by Luther Kennicut, 1777 March 4 (Box 1)
    - Orders to Lieut. Barns from Col. Wm. Shepard; Springfield [at bottom is a note identifying Barns as Barrows], 1781 August 25 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Issaac Barrons to 2d lieutenancy, signed by John Hancock, 1781 August 15 (Box 1)
    - Certificate of service in the Revolutionary War for Thomas Haney, signed by John Haney; Boston [with note by Haney making a plea for a pension], 1818 July (Box 1)
    - Statement of service in the Revolutionary War by Thomas Haney; Boston, 1818 March 18 (Box 1)
    - A return of Capt. Abijah Childs' company in the 25th Regiment, 1776 February 16 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Simon Edgel to captaincy; signed by Perez Morton and 15 others, 1776 December 10 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Simeon Edgell to captaincy; signed by John Avery and 15 others, 1773 July 10 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Benjamin Edghill to captaincy; signed by John Avery and 15 others, 1778 July 7 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Daniel Gallushee to lieutenancy by Congress; signed by John Hancock, 1775 May 19 (Box 1)
    - Appointment of Richard Frothingham to office of Principle Field Commissary, signed by Richard Peters, 1781 June 1 (Box 1)
    - Certificate of continuance on Pension Roll to Caesar Glover, signed by I. L. Edwards, 1820 October 20 (Box 1)
    - Circular letter ordering the return of census figures from the District Court of the United States at Boston, signed by M. Van Buren, 1830 June 4 (Box 1)
    - Acknowledgment of the receipt of copyright lists from the Clerk of the District Court of the United States at Boston, signed by Daniel Webster, 1841 April 13 (Box 1)
  - [Originals formerly in the possession of Mr. McKay of Meadville, PA]
    - Warrant from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Philadelphia, 1780 August 8 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Philadelphia, 1784 August 21 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Chester, 1779 July 18 (Box 2)
    - Copy of letter from B. Lincoln to Samuel Hodgdon, 1782 January 1 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Peter Boyer to James Boyer; Boston, 1780 September 15 (Box 2)
    - Citation to James Boyer to appear at court-marial of Gen. St. Clair; White Plains, 1778 August 4 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Peter Boyer to James Boyer; Boston, 1779 October 26 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Richard Frothingham to James boyer; Tappon, 1780 August 20 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Alexander Hodgdon to James Boyer; Boston, 1779 February 20 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Brig. Gen. Knox to James Boyer; camp in New Jersey, 1780 October 30 (Box 2)
    - Instructions from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Philadelphia, 1780 October 26 (Box 2)
    - Appointment by EbenrStevens of James Boyer to office of Deputy Commissary General, 1778 April 24 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Richard Frothingham to James Boyer, 1780 June 5 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Philadelphia, 1781 October 14 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Sam Hodgdon to James Boyer; Boston, 1779 March 10 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Peter Boyer to James Boyer; Boston, 1779 August 24 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Peter Boyer to James Boyer; Boston [with copy of Treasurer's note appended], 1780 July 6 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Nathaniel Parvin to Thomas Jones; Burlington, 1781 December 10 (Box 2)
    - Letter from T. Jones to James Boyer; camp near Williamsburg, 1781 September 13 (Box 2)
    - Letter from Richard Frothingham to James Boyer; Artillery Park [contains remarks by an eye witness on the execution of Major André], 1780 October 3 (Box 2)